Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/mayank-kachhwaha-46785117 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Financial Modeling Analytics Business Analytics

Languages

Hindi

Honors-Awards

Entrepreneur - Forbes India 30 under 30

Mayank Kachhwaha

Founder at IndiaLends | Forbes 30 u 30 India

Summary

Forbes India '30 Under 30' Entrepreneur, with over seven years of global experience in the credit risk and lending industry. Co-founded IndiaLends - India's fastest growing credit underwriting and risk analytics platform that connects consumers with financial institutions to get the best credit products - in 2015. Has experience working in risk assessment and consumer analytics, financial modelling, and financial operations design roles in the US, UK, and Indian Markets. Alumnus, Bachelors of Technology, IIT-Madras.

Demonstrated Strengths include Quantitative and Business Modelling, Business Research and Design, Capital Fundraising, Market Research and Digital Analytics, New Product Development and Product Launch, Project Management, and Business Process Design and Management.

Specialities: Expertise in marketing, credit and financial analysis, use of modelling to assess risk and evaluate credit worthiness, business cycle forecasting, SAS based quantitative data mining, loss forecast modelling, BASEL based econometric loss provisioning, fraud analytics and credit governance.

Experience

IndiaLends

Founder

March 2015 - Present (5 years 6 months)

Indialends is a credit underwriting and analytics platform for unsecured consumer lending. Available on both the web and mobile, IndiaLends uses proprietary algorithms to connect borrowers with the right financial institutions. Indialends also provides data analytics and risk scoring services along with a loan management platform to financial institutions. It has also helped automate workflows and risk assessments thereby making the loan disbursal process much more efficient.

IndiaLends is run by a team of bankers and data scientists with multiple years of experience in consumer and small business credit. For further information, please visit www.indialends.com

Capital One

6 years 3 months

Manager, Credit risk advisor
July 2012 - September 2014 (2 years 3 months)

Credit Governance Advisor in the UK Credit Risk Management team

Senior Associate, Loss Forecasting June 2011 - June 2012 (1 year 1 month)

Loss Forecasting in the UK Credit Risk Management team

Senior Associate, Credit Policy June 2010 - May 2011 (1 year) Bangalore, India

Small Business Card Acquisition credit policy team

Associate, Fraud Strategy July 2008 - May 2010 (1 year 11 months) Bangalore, India

Worked in the US card fraud strategy team

Education

Indian Institute of Technology, Madras
B Tech, Mechanical Engineering (2004 - 2008)